const qBank = [
	{
		id: 1,
		question: "'OS' computer abbreviation usually means ?",
		options: ["Order of Significance", "Open Software", "Operating System", "Optical Sensor"],
		answer: "Operating System",
	},
	{
		id: 2,
		question: "'.MOV' extension refers usually to what kind of file?",
		options: ["MS Office document", "Image file", "Audio file", "Animation/movie file"],
		answer: "Animation/movie file",
	},
	{
		id: 3,
		question: "What does EPROM stand for?",
		options: ["Electric Programmable Read Only Memory", "Erasable Programmable Read Only Memory", "Evaluable Philotic Random Optic Memory", "Every Person Requires One Mind"],
		answer: "Erasable Programmable Read Only Memory"
	},
	{
		id: 4,
		question: "Larger buildings may be supplied with a medium voltage electricity supply, and will required a substation or mini-sub. What is the main item of equipment contained in these?",
		options: ["Transformer", "Transponder", "Transducer", "Converter"],
		answer: "Transformer"
	},
	{
		id: 5,
		question: "The input used by an antenna or cable to a TV set uses frequencies called...?",
		options: ["IF", "RF", "AF", "SAP"],
		answer: "RF"
	},
	{
		id: 6,
		question: "The purpose of choke in tube light is ?",
		options: ["To decrease the current", "To increase the current", "To increase the voltage momentarily", "To decrease the voltage momentarily"],
		answer: "To increase the voltage momentarily"
	},
    {
		id: 7,
		question: "What is Sea Ice?",
		options: ["Frozen CO2", "Frozen sea water", "Frozen salt", "Frozen sugar"],
		answer: "Frozen sea water"
	},
	
	{
		id: 8,
		question: "'.INI' extension refers usually to what kind of file?",
		options: ["Image file", "System file", "Hypertext related file", "Image Color Matching Profile file"],
		answer: "System file"
	},
	{
		id: 9,
		question: "What does the term PLC stand for??",
		options: ["Programmable Logic Controller", "Program List Control", "Piezo Lamp Connector", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Programmable Logic Controller"
	},
	{
		id: 10,
		question: "Made from a variety of materials, such as carbon, which inhibits the flow of current...?",
		options: ["Inductor", "Choke", "Resistor", "Capacitor"],
		answer: "Resistor"
	},
	{
		id: 11,
		question: "What is the name of India’s first space-based observatory, to be launched in September 2023?",
		options: ["Arun-L1", "Surya-L1", "Kathir-L1", "Aditya-L1"],
		answer: "Aditya-L1"
	},
	{
		id: 12,
		question: "Which of these was the first cell phone to use the Android operating system?",
		options: ["T-Mobile G1", "BlackBerry Storm", "Samsung Rant", "LG Voyager"],
		answer: "T-Mobile G1"
	},
	{
		id: 13,
		question: "‘V2X technology’, which was seen in the news, is related to _______________ .",
		options: ["Automobile", "Computer Graphics", "Printing Currency notes", "Electronic Gadgets"],
		answer: "Automobile"
	},
	{
		id: 14,
		question: "What technology helps make telephone calls over the Internet possible?",
		options: ["VoIP", "Bluetooth", "Ethernet", "None of the above"],
		answer: "VoIP"
	},
	{
		id: 15,
		question: "Who founded Apple Computer?",
		options: ["Sundar Pichai", "Steve Jobs", "Bill Gates", "Sheryl Sandberg"],
		answer: "Steve Jobs"
	},
	{
		id: 16,
		question: "What was the first interactive computer-graphics program?",
		options: ["CorelDRAW", "Notepad", "Adobe Photoshop", "Sketchpad"],
		answer: "Sketchpad"
	},
	{
		id: 17,
		question: "In what year was Google founded?",
		options: ["2002", "1998", "1978", "2005"],
		answer: "1998"
	},
	{
		id: 18,
		question: "A network designed to allow communication within an organization is called:",
		options: ["the World Wide Web", "an intranet", "a browser", "the Internet"],
		answer: "an intranet"
	},
	{
		id: 19,
		question: "What device converts digital signals to analog signals?",
		options: ["motherboard", "central processing unit (CPU)", "transistor", "modem"],
		answer: "modem"
	},
	{
		id: 20,
		question: "What feature is often used to identify whether a visitor to a Web site is human or not?",
		options: ["General Problem Solver", "DENDRAL", "CAPTCHA", "CYC"],
		answer: "CAPTCHA"
	},
	{
		id: 21,
		question: "Which of these was the world''s first business computer?",
		options: ["LEO", "IBM 1401", "HP-85", "Apple II"],
		answer: "LEO"
	},
	{
		id: 22,
		question: "When was Microsoft founded?",
		options: ["1965", "1975", "1999", "2004"],
		answer: "1975"
	},
	{
		id: 23,
		question: "Who is credited with inventing the term 'software engineer'?",
		options: ["Margaret Hamilton", "Tommy Flowers", "Grace Hopper", "Evelyn Granville"],
		answer: "Margaret Hamilton"
	},
	{
		id: 24,
		question: "What is the name of the digital file format that was devised in 1987 to reduce the size of images and short animations?",
		options: ["JPEG", "TIFF", "GIF", "PNG"],
		answer: "GIF"
	},
	{
		id: 25,
		question: "What type of electromagnetic waves does Wi-Fi use?",
		options: ["radio waves", "microwaves", "gamma rays", "infrared waves"],
		answer: "radio waves"
	},
]

export default qBank;
